<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.asyla.org//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.asyla.org//"/>
  <updated>2013-10-27T16:33:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.asyla.org//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidelines]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2012/02/13/guidelines/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2012/02/13/guidelines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Some daily recommendations</h2>

<!--more-->


<h3>SLEEP</h3>

<p>First and foremost, get 7-9 hours of sleep.  In a completely dark and quiet room. Completely dark means just that.  Get rid of all those lights and close the curtains.  If you can see your hands its too bright.  Relax prior to going to bed.  Try to wake without needing an alarm.</p>

<h3>EAT</h3>

<p>In short, veggies fill you up.  Fat removes hunger.  Protein is needed to build muscle.  Muscle burns calories.</p>

<p>For protein, you will want ~1lb of lean meat, eggs or fish per day.  Preferably grass fed/free range.  Organ meat (ie liver) is especially good.  Don’t be afraid of fat.  It provides the satiety signal in your brain and is vital for good health.  Use coconut oil and olive oil.   Don’t forget to eat lots of varied veggies.  Drink plenty of water.  <a href="http://www.penzeys.com/">Penzey&rsquo;s</a> is your friend and they are local.  Visit regularly.</p>

<p>Buy quality food.  In general it is safe to assume anything with a food label is likely bad for you.  Do not assume that the food label lists all ingredients and provides no indication of what has been done during processing.  The fact that it has been processed should be the first warning to avoid a product.  That it is called a product should be second.</p>

<p>Know what you are eating.  Cook your own food and take control of your diet.  The longer you eat this way the better whole foods taste.  Correspondingly, processed food tastes worse.</p>

<p>Resources:</p>

<p><a href="http://5by5.tv/paleo/">http://5by5.tv/paleo/</a></p>

<p>This is a great introduction to Paleo and related topics.  Start with episode 1 and work your way forward.  Lots of good information here.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.everydaypaleo.com/">http://www.everydaypaleo.com/</a></p>

<p>Want recipe ideas?  Want to know what it is like to live with the Paleo diet and raise a family?  This is the place to look.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.robbwolf.com/">http://www.robbwolf.com/</a></p>

<p>Want to learn about Paleo in more detail?   Robb Wolf is a good resource.</p>

<p>If your goal is to loose weight, follow the above plan and make it a point to be hungry for the next meal.  If your goal is to gain muscle, eat enough that you aren’t.  The best strategy for many would be to build muscle first which will make loosing fat far easier.</p>

<p>Don’t forget that the amount of fat you consume will directly control how quickly you get hungry.  A great experiment to try:  For breakfast, eat only 1 sweet potato and 3 hardboiled eggs.  Note what time you get hungry prior to lunch (for me, 3hrs later).  Next day, eat the same thing with 1Tbs of coconut oil (110cal).  Note when (if?) you get hungry.  If you really wish to experiment, add the same number of calories worth of plain sugar and note the time.  It should be the shortest of all.</p>

<h3>EXERCISE</h3>

<p>Mobility is incredibly important.  Without a full range of motion you are setting yourself up for injury.  Find what is lacking and work on it at least once a week.  Avoid things that limit mobility.  Straighten that back.  Get up from your desk at least once an hour.  Sleep on your back with a flat pillow, etc.</p>

<p>Be consistent with your program.  You will never improve anything if you don’t show up but hey its your life.</p>

<p>You probably aren’t strong enough so do something about it by lifting heavy things often.  Done fear the barbell.  Respect it and then own it.  Learn how to do the Olympic lifts <em>correctly</em>.  This takes time so be patient but is well worth the effort.  Do them often as part of your workout.  Focus on the quality and range of the movement before even thinking about the time it takes to do a workout.  If you cant do the motion correctly, ask for help, go slower and use a lighter weight.  There is no shame in this.  You will improve and that’s better then doing something stupid and hurting yourself.</p>

<p>Track your progress!!  Write everything down in a notebook.  You cant improve if you don’t know what you did.  If you aren’t improving, figure out what you are doing wrong.  Ask for help as needed.  After a certain point, the beginner gains will taper off.  Don’t be discouraged as this is to be expected.  That’s when the real training begins.</p>

<p>Learn your limits.  No not those.  Your head is just messing with you.  I mean your physical limits.  If you think you cant do something then you wont.  That has nothing to do with whether or not you are actually physically capable of it.  Once you know your physical limitations, ignore them and go find our what your genetic limitations are.</p>

<p>Maintain focus.  There are many fun and cool things out there.  CrossFit dabbles in many of them.  If you choose to go exploring, work out a plan and STICK TO IT for at least a couple months.  Randomly jumping around to the next cool thing wont do you any favors.</p>

<p>Thoughts about CrossFit MetCons:  If you wish to have good endurance and maintain a lighter build, go with lighter weights and go really fast.  If you are more interested in strength, go heavier and slower.  However, if you are already fairly light/thin, do yourself a favor and first focus on strength.  The rest will come easier.</p>

<h3>RECOVER</h3>

<p>Less is more.  First you need to learn what that means.  Then you need to learn to actually live it.  This applies to all aspects of your life but as a starting point, remove the stress.</p>

<p>You can not recover when stressed.  You also will NOT recover when chronically fatigued.</p>

<p>If you are injured, then you need to recover!  Obvious huh?  Apparently not.  That means you need to actually focus on recovering and not continuing to make things worse.  Don’t do something that you will regret for the rest of your life just because you got caught up in the moment.</p>

<h3>EVERYTHING ELSE</h3>

<p>A positive attitude goes a long way to improve quality of life.  Always strive to improve yourself.  Be curious, learn something, practice a new skill, expand your horizons, etc but most of all, LIVE and HAVE FUN!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tonsillolith and friends]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2012/01/01/tonsillolith-and-friends/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2012/01/01/tonsillolith-and-friends</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For as long as I can remember, Ive had regular occurrences of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tonsillolith">tonsilloliths</a> (aka tonsil stones).  The only reason Im even bringing this up now is because last week I had my first one in about a year.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>These things are more of an annoyance then anything.  From reading about it, tonsillolith can manifest in different ways.  In my case they generally get quite large in a half day or so.  Fortunately they can be popped out fairly easily and long ago I learned that if I dont do something about it within a day of it forming then Ill get sick.  The progression is a sore throat which then moves up into my sinuses which then becomes a full blown cold.  Fun.  I would have one form every now an again but it was at least once a month.  I just got into the habit of checking my tonsils on a regular basis and as long as I did then I wouldnt get sick.  The thing is, when I went Paleo at the beginning of 2011, this completely went away.  And I didnt even notice.  It was somewhere around Fall when I even realized.  Weird.</p>

<p>So by going Paleo I removed, among other things, all grains from my diet.  And last Tuesday I had a serving of white rice.  We were at a restaurant (Qdoba) and I completely forgot to tell the person no rice until it was too late.  Oh well.  Its white rice.  How bad can it be?  <a href="http://robbwolf.com/">Robb Wolf</a> even has made statements to the effect that white rice is the least bad type.  Plus I was hungry which tends to make rationalizations like this possible.  Anyrate, it had formed by Wed.  Meanwhile, Im still dealing with the other after effects I get from grains:  acne and generally just not feeling quite right.  Generally if I get a low dose of soy or wheat, the &ldquo;not quite right&rdquo; feeling creeps up and subsides the same day.  Acne takes a little longer to show and pretty consistently forms the next day.  All of the major effects are generally out of my system within a day or two (not counting the healing time for the acne).  In this case from eating a scoop (~1C?) of rice, its still going after 5.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supplements]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/29/supplements/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/29/supplements</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Supplements</h2>

<p>The topic of supplements has come up now and again so I thought I should post something about it.</p>

<p>I should mention at this point that Ive run across a fair number of articles citing research showing that large doses of vitamins/mineral are not good for you in the long run.  As well as large amounts of antioxidents, fruit extract, etc.  As always, its best to obtain everything from your diet and environment and, well, supplement the little bit that is missing.</p>

<p>Here is the list of what Im taking on a daily basis:</p>

<!--more-->




<div>
<ul>
    <li>ZMA</li>
    <li>Vitamin D</li>
    <li>NOW Super Enzymes</li>
    <li>Carlsons Fish Oil</li>
    <li>Glucosamine Chondroitin MSM</li>
    <li>Protein powder</li>
</ul>
</div>


<p>You might notice, I <em>dont</em> have the ubiquitous multivitamin on the list.  Since, Im following the <a href="http://thepaleodiet.com/">Paleo</a> diet, Im getting all the nutrients the multivitamin contains.  Since overdosing is bad, Ill just eliminate that from my diet.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZMA_%28supplement%29">ZMA</a></h3>

<p><strong>Z</strong>inc monomethionine <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aspartate">Aspartate</a> and <strong>M</strong>agnesium <strong>A</strong>spartate (ZMA).  Im taking this for a couple reasons and its primarily for the magnesium as a sleep aid.  It does seem to help somewhat and certainly doesnt hurt either.  Obviously I take this at night.</p>

<p>Whenever I have felt the onset of a cold coming on, Ive taken zinc acetate to lessen the severity and speed up the recovery time.  This was originally based on some research I ran across some years ago on the subject (ie, <a href="http://www.evernote.com/shard/s46/sh/5a6eb8b9-f675-4bff-b4c1-c55924493070/0c78ffa8952066a3efd9914e030c2067">article1</a>, <a href="(http://www.evernote.com/shard/s46/sh/4e5bc5da-019d-4174-a760-0f83981b1808/9d795f3a76cc3650ef51f5d37331a47a">article2</a>).  Now its because I found it works quite well.  Unfortunately the products (<a href="http://www.coldeeze.com/">ColdEze</a> and my preferred <a href="http://www.zicam.com/">Zincum</a> that I found at the store tend to run somewhat low in their doesage rates.  Even worse, they are homeopathic.  As with anything and especially when dealing with homeopathy, make sure you <em>read and understand</em> what the ingredient list says.  Anyrate, at the beginning of the year, in my N=1 experiment I was taking ZMA when I managed to catch a cold.  I wasnt able to get to the store in time for my usual remedies but I still recovered quickly.  Nothing scientific of course but I think it helped.</p>

<p>Now that Ive been <a href="http://thepaleodiet.com/">Paleo</a> for ~10 months now, Im pretty sure I get enough zinc in my diet.  Not sure about the magnesium since some paleo notables (ie <a href="http://robbwolf.com/">Robb Wolf</a>) are supplementing with it themselves.  No way to tell without a blood test which I might do someday.  In the meantime, once I run out of ZMA, Ill likely switch over to <a href="http://www.petergillham.com">Natural Calm</a> and see how I feel.</p>

<h3>Vitamin D</h3>

<p>Im currently taking 2,000 units of this in the morning.  Main thing Ive noticed is that after taking this I started waking up easier.  Somewhere I ran across 10,000 units being about how much is produced by the body in a day.  There is also a good bit talking about min/max blood levels, the problems that occur if you go too far either way (ie: <a href="http://www.evernote.com/shard/s46/sh/137d4184-a71d-4196-bafc-08e4a3ebb86b/a30e61eabf8a8b8f63bac387968a690b">article1</a>, <a href="http://www.evernote.com/shard/s46/sh/6cc6c2f1-ac49-4d31-8603-3227290a2f3c/27ef538a482347c8525c17666ff0d235">article2</a>) and etc.  Since I work at a desk and generally only see the sun on occasion and not having enough info, I started off at 10K units.  About a month later I backed off to 5000 units and never felt any difference.  A week or so after switching to 2000 units and Im having a bit harder time waking up in the morning but thats likely more because I havnt been getting to bed early enough.  I really should do something about the sleep and lack of sun.</p>

<p>Oh, also, I read somewhere that fish oil blocks vitamin D absorbtion which is why I take this in the morning.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.nowfoods.com/">NOW</a> Super Enzymes</h3>

<p>I got this from Robb Wolf&rsquo;s podcast.  Have to say that I was skeptical at first but unlike any other supplement, the effects are fast and noticeable.  Robb&rsquo;s instructions are to increase the dosage by 1 pill per meal until you feel a &ldquo;warming&rdquo; sensation.  Once you reach that point, back off by one pill.  Dont exceed 6 in a meal.  Dont drink a ton of water during the meal because it will be diluted.  I also suggest limiting yourself to, say, 1 pill if you arent eating meat but your mileage may vary.</p>

<h3>Fish Oil</h3>

<p>I take this one at night.  Lately Ive been hearing that the fermented version is supposed to be better, easier to absorb, etc but I havnt really looked into it yet.  Thing is, I have some mixed opinions about the whole topic.  The primary reason to take fish oil is for the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Omega-3_fatty_acid">Omega-3 fatty acids</a>.  We dont get enough.  Or rather, we get FAR too many <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Omega-6_fatty_acid">Omega-6 fatty acids</a>.  The discussion about why is far outside the scope of this.  Go read/listen about the paleo diet for a while if you care about the details.  Anyrate, by supplementing with fish oil, we arent fixing the problem.  Yeah, the ratios are getting closer to balanced but the total quantities are way out of wack.  Better would be to remove the problem in the first place.  However, grass fed meat isnt exactly stocked at the grocery here and the other sources are a bit more difficult (and more expensive).  Course, fish oil isnt exactly cheap either.  While Im pondering this delemma, Im taking a fairly low dosage.</p>

<h3>Glucosamine Chondroitin MSM</h3>

<p>I started taking this on a regular basis because my joints are creaky and 2 doctors suggested that I should do it.  So I took the hint.  I find its only a minor improvement if at all.  I might stop for a month when I run out to see if I notice any differences.  Currently taking <a href="http://www.osteobiflex.com/">Osteo Bi-Flex</a> since it is easy to find and seems to have the highest concentration per pill (read cheapest) but I kinda like the one from <a href="http://www.nutracorp.com/">KAL</a> because it doesnt have the huge dose of sodium like the others.</p>

<h3>Protein powder</h3>

<p>Almost entirely based on an <a href="http://www.evernote.com/shard/s46/sh/f8e2a55a-d240-42e8-9455-9c0a901814c6/e27d7e251972bac608851b76d490b5ac%20">article</a> I read, Ive been taking 30g of protein powder after workouts for the leucine.  If anyone is interested, Im purchasing my own custom blend from <a href="http://www.trueprotein.com/">True Protein</a> which is made up of the following:</p>

<ul>
    <li>25% Hydrolyzed Casein (bitter)</li>
    <li>75% Hydrolyzed Whey Protein Super Grade (chalky)</li>
</ul>


<p>The casein is new this time around.  This is another N=1 experiment but overall I do feel that the protein it has been helping.  Ill keep tracking and see how I feel good enough about it to buy more when I run out of this batch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Under Seat Box v2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/27/under-seat-box-v2/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/27/under-seat-box-v2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Greenspeed GTR has a good bit of empty space under the seat.  I tend to haul a lot of stuff and the pictures below are of the latest box Ive made:</p>

<!--more-->


<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_15_36_IMG_6172.JPG" width="306" height="204">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_52_03_IMG_6152.JPG" width="306" height="204">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_52_33_IMG_6153.JPG" width="306" height="204">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_52_58_IMG_6154.JPG" width="306" height="204">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_54_16_IMG_6155.JPG" width="306" height="204">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_56_57_IMG_6156.JPG" width="306" height="204">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_57_23_IMG_6157.JPG" width="306" height="204"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexbeam]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/27/hexbeam/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/27/hexbeam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some quick pictures of my HexBeam ham radio antenna and its mount.  It covers 6m through 20m.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_12_16_41_14_IMG_5617.JPG" width="221" height="330">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_12_16_41_37_IMG_5618.JPG" width="189" height="126">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_12_16_41_47_IMG_5619.JPG" width="227" height="340">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_12_16_41_55_IMG_5620.JPG" width="210" height="315">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_12_16_43_55_IMG_5621.JPG" width="206" height="137">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_12_16_45_12_IMG_5622.JPG" width="195" height="130">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_12_16_45_38_IMG_5623.JPG" width="191" height="127">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_24_17_35_15_IMG_5624.JPG" width="234" height="350">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_05_24_17_35_50_IMG_5625.JPG" width="234" height="350"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Fit]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/27/getting-fit/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2011/10/27/getting-fit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This article was originally posted by Ryan Atkins who runs <a href="http://www.crossfitmilwaukee.com/">Crossfit Milwaukee</a> on his blog at <a href="http://strongrealizations.blogspot.com/">strongrealizations.blogspot.com</a>.  I thought this might be a good starting point for further posts later on so Ive reproduced it here:</p>

<!--more-->


<p>My goal was to loose weight</p>

<p>I know Robb Wolf says to throw out the scale but I like numbers.  So I give you a chart instead:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/11.png" width="509" height="296"></p>

<p>The above weight history goes back into high school (155lb) to show my climb into obesity that was only marred by the occasional attempt to loose weight.  There was no real exercise to speak of but I was always a bit of a cyclist.  Somewhere around 1999 I started commuting to work and was averaging 1800-2000 miles a year.</p>

<p>The cluster of dots in 2000-2002 was the result of my first attempt to loose weight.  My methodology at the time was to exercise more.  A group of us would use the weight room in the building and would climb stairs.  No real structure.  Needless to say it didn’t last long and didn’t really change anything.</p>

<p>Somewhere around 2003 is when my weight broke 200lbs and cycling started to become difficult.  Each year after that I would have more and more problems such as chafing.</p>

<p>I think it was 2007 when my left knee sustained an early season cycling injury which prevented me from riding the rest of the year.  At the time I blamed the new set of pedals.  Now I don’t believe that they were at fault but was the final straw.  From that point on, my knee was a constant problem.  By 2009 both knees were almost constantly hurting.  I couldn’t goto a movie without my knees seizing up.  Airplane rides were murder.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/21.png" width="395" height="226"></p>

<p>It wasn’t until 2009 that I made my next attempt and was when I bought a used Concept2 rower that fall.  I saw a loss of weight for a little bit but my eating habits soon took care of that.  Weight overall was still climbing.  When I was researching about rowing is when I first heard about CrossFit but I didn’t really pay too much attention at the time.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/3.png" width="381" height="206"></p>

<p>2010 was a really bad year at work because we were acquired Oct 1, 2009 and my co-worker wisely found other employment in March.  Hours, workload, stress and weight went through the roof.  I barely even saw the bike much less rode it.  It was June when my weight hit 220lbs with no signs of stopping.  Interestingly enough even at this point some people still didn’t believe I was overweight.</p>

<p>Since I had no real control over anything else, I decided to loose weight.  I now know there are far better ways to go about that but Ill outline what I did starting June:</p>

<p>First, I decided to eliminate 500 Cal/day.  No, I wasn’t weighing/measuring my food or anything.  It was simply a matter of eating less of everything.  Since I knew that 1lb fat is 3500 Cal, this should work.  And it did.  Sorta.</p>

<p>At some point I ran across a discussion about some research about the addictive nature of sugar.  It really hit home as I have absolutely no self-control when it comes to anything sweet.  So I decided to treat my sugar addiction and went cold-turkey.  That was a rough couple of weeks but it got easier as the cravings went away.  This also helped my weight loss but not too much.</p>

<p>What made the really big difference was the idea that I should actually by hungry before I eat a meal.  I started making it a point of eating 3 meals a day but I would only eat just enough to make it through till the next meal.  This was <strong>quite</strong> effective and the weight was just falling off.  Of course, the body goes into starvation mode and so you have to keep eating <strong>less</strong> to continue this process.  Near the end, I was basically eating snacks to tide me over to the next meal but interestingly hunger levels weren’t really all that bad.  Somewhere in the middle of this phase I noticed that vegetables and such started tasting better and so I started gravitating my diet in that direction.</p>

<p>Work started easing up slightly late Nov, 2009.  Now that I had gotten my weight down to a more manageable ~178lbs, I knew I needed to do <em>something</em> or it will just go back so I started rowing again.  Meanwhile I also started researching fitness programs.  I knew the globo gyms weren’t the answer but I didn’t know what was.  At some point I recalled CrossFit again and so focused my full attention in that direction.  It looked tough but it lined up with everything that I was interested in.  Did a quick search and found that there was a local gym not too far from work.  After building up my nerve, I signed up for the free Sat class on Dec 4.</p>

<p>That class nearly killed me.  I was also hooked.  I spent the rest of the month reading, researching, and generally trying to apply what I learned from the class</p>

<p>Onramp started Jan 10, 2010 and I was ~184lbs.  The benchmark WOD (shuttle runs, air squats, push-ups, sit-ups) nearly killed me.  I spent the entire month in pain and coughing.  But I was improving and enjoying every minute of it.</p>

<p>Onramp introduced the Paleo diet and so I started reading about that.   I immediately cut out wheat from my diet and promptly went into withdrawal.   Cutting out sugar was easy.  The weight loss was easy.  I was dreaming about bread.  Just the thought of bread would cause cravings.  This lasted for a couple months.  Meanwhile I was refining my diet more and more.  I was mainly eating low density carbs with some protein.</p>

<p>My goal became to loose fat.  And perhaps not die after a workout.</p>

<p>By the end of the onramp, I knocked 1:29 off my time.  Signed up for unlimited and have been attending an average of 4.3 days/week.  For my 6 month anniversary, I knocked yet another 1:06 off my benchmark time.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/41.png" width="468" height="266"></p>

<p>By the March 19, 2011, my weight had stabilized at 167lbs.  I had lost ~55lbs.  Went from a tight 38” waist, down to a comfortable 32”.  Went through 2 belts.  I was pretty consistent about 1” off the waist per 10lb lost.  I was now the same clothing size that I was in high school but weighed 10lb more and was stronger.  My mother was kind enough to say I looked like I had consumption.  (<em>sigh</em>)  Ok, I admit the old clothes were a bit baggy but my mid March I finally had a body composition that I wanted for for the first time in my life.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/5.png" width="407" height="216"></p>

<p>Since my weight stabilized for a week or so and good enough is never good enough, I started wondering what % fat I was at and if I could improve it any.  So more research, some learning, some practice and after some months eventually started to get some consistent numbers.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/6.png" width="418" height="225"></p>

<p>Note that with such things, since the data points are calculated, the key is to utilize a consistent and repeatable testing methodology.  The numbers may be inaccurate but they all should have roughly the same amount of inaccuracy.  The nice thing is, this work showed me what I already knew from me results in the WoDs.  I was building muscle, loosing fat but not really changing weight.  I should also point out that the “wild” fluxuations in % fat are more due to the scale of the chart but are generally accurate in the 2<sup>nd</sup> half.  Early on its from me dialing in my diet.  There was the incident of a really long car trip, a giant bag of almonds and an even larger bag of jerky in July.  And then it was the yo-yo affect of me behaving one week and living off fruit the next</p>

<p>By Jul, I was starting to reevaluate my diet and fitness goals again mostly because I simply need more muscle and Im impatient.  I determined that I wasn’t eating enough protein, was getting virtually no fat and generally was living off of a mountain of greens at each meal.  It was time to make some changes.  I tinkered a bit and came up with a plan late Aug.  I switched over to a lot of protein with a more reasonable amount of fat and switched over to high density carbs.  I also cut back the fruit to one piece or less a day.  Finally, I started taking protein powder (specifically one high in Leucine) after workouts.  By the way, after this many months of Paleo, I find that plain squash actually tastes good.  The Paleo challenge was announced soon after this decision (good timing really).</p>

<p>Starting Sept, my goal changed to gain muscle for ~12 weeks.</p>

<p>Except there was one (major) problem.  My job.  Fortunately, I found a new one and started on Oct 1.    However, one word of advice:  DON’T try to do a Paleo challenge while changing jobs!  I’m sure you can easily pick out in the graph which 3 weeks were affected.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/7.png" width="490" height="259"></p>

<p>Despite the diet disruptions, the lines are trending in the right directions and I’ve gained ~3.5lbs lean weight in ~2months which is considerably faster then my estimations for earlier.</p>

<p>Here are my before and after pictures for the challenge.  During this time, I was doing the Starting Strength Advance Novice Program:</p>

<p>9/3/2011</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/8.png" width="243" height="643">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/9.png" width="182" height="640"></p>

<p>10/9/2011</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/10.png" width="246" height="658">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/111.png" width="167" height="657"></p>

<p>Ok, I know, not much difference.  But trust me when I say this is incredibly different from a year ago.  Or even from January.  Too bad I didn’t take pictures back then.</p>

<p>In March I generally had everyone gang up on me and forced me to get a regular doctor.  He ordered up a blood test:</p>

<table style="width: 441px;" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Date</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center"><strong>Units</strong></p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center"><strong>Range</strong></p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center"><strong>3/19/11</strong></p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center"><strong>8/27/11</strong></p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65">
<p align="center"><strong>10/8/11</strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Fasting Status</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">TRUE</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">FALSE</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65">
<p align="center">TRUE</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Glucose</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">65-100</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">76</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Hemoglobin A1C</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">%</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">3.0-6.0</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">5.3%</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>BUN</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">9-25</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">15</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">17</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Creatinine</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">.45-1.26</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">1.18</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">1.4</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Alkaline Phosphatase</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">U/L</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">28-126</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">65</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">81</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Total Bilirubin</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">.2-1.3</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">0.6</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">0.5</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>SGOT (AST)</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">U/L</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">14-59</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">33</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">44</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>SGPT (ALT)</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">U/L</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">9-72</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">22</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">32</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>GGT (GGTP)</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">U/L</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">2-65</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">9</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Total Protein</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">g/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">6.3-8.3</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">7.3</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">7.4</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Albumin</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">g/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">3.5-5.0</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">4.6</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">4.8</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Globulin</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">g/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">1.0-4.0</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">2.6</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Triglycerides</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">35-149</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">80</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">70</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65">
<p align="center">48</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Cholesterol</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">100-199</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">214</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">194</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65">
<p align="center">188</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Cholesterol - LDL (calculated)</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">0-99</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">153</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">119</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65">
<p align="center">123</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Cholesterol - HDL</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">40-200</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">45</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">61</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65">
<p align="center">55</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Cholesterol - Non-HDL (calculated)</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45">
<p align="center">mg/dL</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54">
<p align="center">0-190</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51">
<p align="center">169</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="179"><strong>Cholesterol/HDL Cholesterol Ratio</strong></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="45"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="54"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="51"></td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="47">
<p align="center">3.2</p>
</td>
<td valign="bottom" nowrap="nowrap" width="65"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>Needless to say, he wasn’t happy with my cholesterol and promptly started talking about medication.  I politely declined so he scheduled a 6 month followup to see how I was doing.  Im pretty sure the intent was to build a case for putting me on meds but I wanted to see what the Paleo diet would do for me.  As you can see from the chart, Robb Wolf is telling the truth.  The funny thing is that my doctor, who was quite impressed with the improvement, was very insistent that I should eat oatmeal.  I politely declined that too.  At least he stopped trying to medicate me.  I think Ill aim for March to get another test done.  Perhaps Ill get them to do more then just cholesterol too.</p>

<p>Im curious to see where Ill be in Jan…..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FWDMBBLR]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/13/fwdmbblr/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/13/fwdmbblr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/FWDMBBLR.png" width="566" height="197"></p>

<!--more-->


<p>This is a work in progress.  I want to have a &ldquo;go fast&rdquo; recumbent because my <a href="http://www.greenspeed.com.au/">Greenspeed</a> GTR isnt built for sustained speed and now has way to much stuff on it anyways.</p>

<p>It is a front wheel drive, moving bottom bracket, low racer design with rear suspension and, if I can manage it, front suspension as well.</p>

<hr />

<p>2010-06-13:  Currently waiting for the main body tube to come back from <a href="http://www.wagnercompanies.com/">Wagner</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pannier]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/pannier/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/pannier</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first pannier that I had designed some years ago and is the one I use whenever I ride.  Its just the right size to hold my clothes and shoes when commuting to  work.  But then why would I design something something that I didnt like&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_06_55_IMG_6164.JPG" width="531" height="354"></p>

<!--more-->


<p>For features, there is a pocket on either side in convenient locations, and  there are 3 flat pockets on the front.  There is also a large pocket  inside to hold maps and the like.  The top flap covers the zipper, the straps are intended to remove strain from the zipper and tighten everything up.</p>

<p>The fabric is a coated nylon.  I think it came from  outdoor fabric supply but I forget the name.  The light colored stripes are reflective fabric.  I believe its something from 3M and came from the same supplier.  The webbing is sewn onto the top flap and buckles into pieces sewn into the bottom.  The shoulder strap came from somewhere.  The back is Cordera (backpack cloth) which also covers the bottom of the bag.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_08_37_IMG_6166.JPG" width="276" height="184">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_09_17_IMG_6167.JPG" width="278" height="186"></p>

<p>The mounting hardware is from <a href="http://www.arkel-od.com/">Arkel </a>which you can buy separately  at a reasonable price.  Arkel has a newer style which is fancier and,  IMO, not as easy to use.  It used to be possible to request this older  style but I dont know if they still sell it anymore.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_07_42_IMG_6165.JPG" width="348" height="232"></p>

<p>Here you can see how that bracket is attached.  The yellow stuff is  Coroplat (corrugated plastic) which gives the bracket something to  attach to as well as keeps the corners out the spokes.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_10_27_IMG_6169.JPG" width="286" height="178">
<img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_09_59_IMG_6168.JPG" width="265" height="176"></p>

<p>This photo is showing a little fabric cover hiding the mounting hardware  and bungee/hook.  It makes for a cleaner look and keeps the parts from  causing too much trouble when carrying the bag.  Prolly should have made  the flap a little wider as the ends of the bungee tend to stick out.   Also, the Velcro isnt working as well as it used to.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_10_49_IMG_6170.JPG" width="278" height="185"></p>

<p>You may notice that this isnt exactly a waterproof bag.  Thats by design.  The idea is to not worry about waterproof.  Waterproof is heavy, expensive and/or fragile.  Instead, this is intended to control the water which it does very well.  Anything I carry on the bike gets put inside a (generally waterproof)  stuffsack or plastic bag anyways so why not design something that takes advantage of that.  The flap over the top does a good job of shedding falling water.  The Coroplast back deflects the water from the wheel.  The bottom is designed to drain water that gets inside.  The only time the insides were truly wet was when the bag got submerged (really deep water that I was dumb enough to ride through) but the contents of the bag still stayed dry.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_11_35_IMG_6171.JPG" width="317" height="472"></p>

<p>I should mention that this is the final version of this bag.  There was a prototype made out of (bright yellow) cotton canvas which I had used for a season.  This final version was actually constructed <em>after</em> the <a href="http://www.asyla.org/2010/06/11/big-panniers/">big panniers</a> and corrected some of the mistakes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Camping Box]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/camping-box/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/camping-box</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pictured here on the back of my bike (trike) is the latest evolution of my coroplast panniers:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_48_55_IMG_6146.JPG" width="437" height="200"></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Probably the biggest inspiration to this was a comment in one of the <a href="http://www.greenspeed.com.au/">Greenspeed</a> newsletters a few years back.  As I recall, they were experimenting with utility designs and had completely eliminated the metal rack and replaced it with a coroplast box.  I liked the idea but didnt want to eliminate the rack (its too useful) and wanted to try putting <em>everything</em> (tent and all) inside the box.</p>

<p>One of the <a href="http://www.gmrbc.org/">GMRBC</a> club members has access to a computer controlled box cutter and was kind enough to cut this out for  me.</p>

<p>Here is a picture of the insides.  To mount it to the rack, I made a ubolt out of a piece of all-thread.  Wing nuts are threaded on from inside.  A piece of string is used to keep the lid from falling open.  I have a piece of nylon window screen glued on to act as a pocket.</p>

<p>The left side is deep enough to hold the tent, sleeping bag, clothes, etc.  The water bladder, rain gear, etc lives in the top layer.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_49_33_IMG_6148.JPG" width="397" height="592"></p>

<p>Good view of one of the front storage boxes here.  These are good for snacks and such but are a tad too high for easy access while riding.  I left holes in the bottom so they dont collect water.  And they nicely hold a quart container of blueberries&hellip;.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_49_46_IMG_6149.JPG" width="400" height="598"></p>

<p>You may have wondered why the right side isnt accessible from top.  Its because I have a kitchen.  Or at least a cupboard.  Pots, pans, stove, fuel, food, etc goes in here.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_50_36_IMG_6151.JPG" width="444" height="294"></p>

<p>Back view here.  I hadnt thought about it at the time but that large flat surface is a huge energy sink.  The front isnt that great either.  I really need to design a more aerodynamic version</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_50_02_IMG_6150.JPG" width="388" height="579"></p>

<p>I originally intended this to be a bit deeper then it is but discovered that it interfered with my derailleur.  Ended up chopping off a couple inches from the whole thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bike Solar Power]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/bike-solar-power/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/bike-solar-power</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quick picture of the bike with a 25W flexible solar panel.  It stays put nicely using a velcro-like fastener on each of the corners.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_49_12_IMG_6147.JPG" width="234" height="350"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Panniers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/big-panniers/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/big-panniers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is my 2<sup>nd</sup> pannier design spurred on by the success of my first design and my renewed interest in bike touring:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_58_56_IMG_6159.JPG" width="327" height="218"></p>

<!--more-->


<p>I only have pictures of the right one but its really a matched set.  Like the earlier design, this is using the <a href="http://www.arkel-od.com/">Arkel</a> mounting system.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_59_06_IMG_6160.JPG" width="339" height="226"></p>

<p>This picture provides a good view of the shape of this bag.  Notice the angle of the front (left side of the picture).  Since this is intended for use on a recumbent, I didnt have to worry about my feet hitting so I sloped it forward and got more room and somewhat better aerodynamics.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_13_59_25_IMG_6161.JPG" width="329" height="219"></p>

<p>The construction is pretty similar to my <a href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/11/pannier/">first pannier</a> but there are some subtle differences.  First, the coroplast backing is not replaceable which is probably a mistake.  Second, if you notice, the bag is holding its shape without anything inside.  The Cordera outer shell is actually a sleeve which has a <em>really</em> fine fiberglass/epoxy sheet inside.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_01_08_IMG_6162.JPG" width="326" height="217"></p>

<p>I like pockets</p>

<p><img src="http://www.asyla.org/images/2009_07_19_14_01_31_IMG_6163.JPG" width="350" height="239"></p>

<p>These panniers do a fairly good job but were somewhat expensive and difficult to make.  I like these bags but I couldnt help but think that I could still do better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Im famous]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/10/im-now-famous/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.asyla.org//blog/2010/06/10/im-now-famous</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&hellip;well, no not really.  But my bike and I did appear in a <a href="http://blog.makezine.com/archive/2010/06/mobile_radios_at_hamvention_2010.html">Make magazine video</a>:</p>

<object classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" width="462" height="278" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/rn7y35hZoU8&amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;color2=0xd0d0d0&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feature=player_detailpage&amp;fs=1" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="462" height="278" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/rn7y35hZoU8&amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;color2=0xd0d0d0&amp;hl=en_US&amp;feature=player_detailpage&amp;fs=1" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object>


<p>My portion was at the Bicycle Mobile Hams of America (<a href="http://www.bmha-hams.org/">BMHA</a>) forum at <a href="http://www.hamvention.org/">Dayton Hamvention</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
